A Guide to the Richmond Urban Institute Archives 1979-1986
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Richmond Urban Institute Archives 1979-1986
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 258
18.1 linear feet
Richmond Urban Institute
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
Donated to Special Collections and Archives by the Executive Board and Moderator of the Richmond Urban Institute on July 20, 1988.
Historical Information
The Richmond Urban Institute was created in 1979 to address problems in the city of Richmond. The goals of the original members included education, mediation, cooperation with other organizations, and development of specific programs to bring about a more unified and just city. The Institute affirmed its religious faith and in communal responsibility, drawing its membership from a broad cross-section of business, religious and community interests. Incorporated as a non-profit organization in February, 1980, RUI employed two Urban Missioners and an Administrative Assistant. Funding for these positions and Institute activities came from an extended foundation grant and fund-raising among local churches and businesses. St. Paul's Episcopal Church was instrumental in providing leadership, funds, and office space for the new organization.
An elected Council and Moderator determine RUI policy, but activities originate in standing committees. Historically, the two committees given greatest attention concern disinvestment and racism/racial polarization. Both committees publish reports and organize workshops to involve citizens and government officials in correcting imbalances in Richmond society and economy. More recently, new committees have been formed to address unemployment, transportation, housing, women and poverty, and grassroots development. Significant programs undertaken include a series of Black-Jewish dialogues, a workshop on the impact of the 1981 federal budget, summer camp programs for city children, and a Summer Youth Employment Program.
The organization was dissolved in 1990.
Scope and Content Information
The Archives is composed of correspondence, reports, publications and general office files, excluding most financial and fundraising information, from 1971 through 1988; but the bulk of the material dates from 1979 to 1985. Series and files on specific issues often include notes, articles, and publications gathered to inform individuals and committees which addressed these needs. Other publications follow the major series. The following issues of Revitalization News have been tranferred to the Richmond Revitalization (M253) file: Vol. 1, Numbers 1-7; Vol. 2, Numbers 1, 4, and 5; Vol. 3, Numbers 1 and 2. All materials not directly pertaining to the activities of the Institute have been returned or have been removed and cataloged and added to the library's collection.
Arrangement
Arrangement
All materials are arranged alphabetically within each series.
Organization
Series I--History of the Richmond Urban Institute (1979-1986)
Series II--Programs, Projects, and Reports (1979-1986)
Series III-- Proposals for Urban Projects (1978-1985)
Series IV--Housing (1979-1986)
Series V--Women and the Family (1976-1986)
Series VI-- Other Urban Issues (1971-1985)
Series VII--Public Relations (1979-1985)
Series VIII--Other Organizations (1979-1988)
Series IX--Reference (1977-1984)
Contents List
- Series I History of the Richmond Urban Institute 1979-1988
  - Administration/Finance Committee 1980-1982 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Administrative Officers 1984-1986 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Announcements 1982-1983 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Annual,Semi-Annual Meetings 1980-1983, 1985 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Audit 1986, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Bus Riders Committee: Ben Campbell's notes (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Bus Riders Committee: Correspondence 1981-1983 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Bus Riders Committee: GRTC Information 1982-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Bus Riders Committee: Meetings 1981-1983 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Bus Riders committee: Miscellaneous 1982-1983 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Bus Riders Committee: News Articles 1981-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Bus Riders Committee: Public Hearing 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Bus Riders Committee Reports by RUI 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Bus Riders Committee: Research 1981-1982, 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 2:5)
  - By-Laws, Certificate of Incorporation 1980-1985, 1988-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Citizen's Transportation Council 1983-1985 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Citizen's Transportation Council 1984-1985 (Box-folder 2:8-9)
  - Co-Missioner Ben Campbell: Reports 1980-1982 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Co-Missioner Ben Campbell: Business 1979-1983 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Co-Missioner Edythe Rogers 1979-1983 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Committee Assignments 1983-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Committee Chairmen 1980, 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Committee Guidelines 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Committees, miscellaneous 1981-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 3:7)
  - Corresondence: Incoming 1979-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 3:8)
  - Correspondence: Incoming 1982-1983 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - Correspondence: Incoming 1983-1988 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Correspondence: Incoming 1984-1986, 1989 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing 1979-1908, n.d. (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing 1981 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing 1982 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing 1983 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing 1983-1986 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing 1984-1986, 1988 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - Council: Announcements 1980-1986 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - Council: Correspondence 1981, 1983-1984, 1986 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - Council Evaluations 1981-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Council Letters of resignation 1980-1986 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Council Meetings 1980 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Council Meetings 1980-1986 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Council Meetings 1981 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - Council Meetings 1982 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Council Meetings 1983 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - Council Meetings 1983-1986 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - Council Meetings 1983-1988 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Council Membership 1981-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Council Members questionnaires 1985, 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Council Retreat questionnaires 1985 (Box-folder 6:6)
  - Council Retreats 1983-1985 (Box-folder 6:7)
  - Directory 1984 (Box-folder 7:1)
  - Education Committee 1980-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 7:2)
  - Executive Committee 1983-1986 (Box-folder 7:3)
  - Executive Committee Meetings 1979, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - Executive Director Sheila Crowley 1983-1984 (Box 7:5)
  - Executive Director David Hoover 1985-1986 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - Fundraising package 1984 (Box-folder 7:7)
  - General Information 1982-1985 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Grassroots Economic Development 1983-1985 (Box-folder 7:8)
  - Grassroots Economic Development Correspondence 1983-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 8:1)
  - Group Relations (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Homeless Committee/Task Force 1984-1985 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Interim Coordinator Julia Seward 1983 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Issues/Programs Procedures Committee 1980-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Mailing lists 1985-1986 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Meetings Richmond Urban Intitute 1983-1988 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Membership Committee 1980-1984 (Box-folder 8:8)
  - Membership Committee Correspondence 1980-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 8:9)
  - Membership Committee Memoranda 1984 (Box-folder 8:10)
  - Membership Committee Meetings 1979-1982, 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 8:11)
  - Membership Conference April 20-21, 1980 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - Membership Conference April 20-21, 1980 (Box-folder 8:12)
  - Membership Conference May 18-19, 1980 (Box-folder 8:13)
  - Membership Conference June 6-7, 1980 (Box-folder 8:14)
  - Membership Conference September 21-22, 1980 (Box-folder 8:15)
  - Membership Conference january 16-17, 1981 (Box-folder 8:16)
  - Membership Letters 1980-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 8:17)
  - Membership Lists 1981-1985 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Membership Lists 1983-1985 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Membership miscellaneous 1983-1988 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Membership questionnaires 1983 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Membership questionnaires Problems (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Memberships potential lists 1984-1985 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Memoranda 1981-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Miscellaneous 1983-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Nominating Committee 1983-1985 (Box-folder 9:9)
  - Notes 1981-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 9:10)
  - Peeples, Edward H. Writings 1964,1979, 1981-1985 (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Personnel 1980-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 9:11)
  - Personnel Job Descriptions 1984-1985 (Box-folder 9:13)
  - Personnel Policies 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Personnel Salaries 1981-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Photographs 1982-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 9:16)
  - Planning Retreat 1982 (Box-folder 9:17)
  - Principles 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 10:1)
  - Printer material: office supplies 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 10:2)
  - Procedures: Elections 1981 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Procedures: Office 1981, 1985 (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Program Screening/Program Oversight Committee 1983, 1985 (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Program Updates 1983 (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Proposals, Goals 1981-1985 (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Proposed Policies 1980, 1982, 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 10:8)
  - Racial and Ethnic Issues Committee 1984-1985 (Box-folder 10:29)
  - Racism/Polarization Committee 1980-1981 (Box-folder 10:10)
  - Reinvestment Committee: Address n.d. (Box-folder 10:11)
  - Reinvestment Committee: Bulletins 1979-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 10:12)
  - Reinvestment Committee: Correspondence 1980-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 10:13)
  - Reinvestiment Committee: Meetings 1980-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 10:14)
  - Reinvestment Committee: Public Relations 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 10:15)
  - Reinvestment Committee: Reports 1979-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 10:16)
  - Reinvestment Committee: Workshop 1981 (Box-folder 10:17)
  - Research Committee 1979-1980 (Box-folder 10:18)
  - Research Documents 1979-1980 (Box-folder 10:19)
  - Retreats 1982-1983, 1985 (Box-folder 10:20)
  - Search Committee 1979-1980, 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Spiritual Perspectives Committee 1980-1981, 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Staff Meeting 1985 (Box-folder 11:3)
  - State Corporation Commission Report 1983 (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Survey on Public Education 1988 (Box-folder 11:5)
  - Task Force on Black Males 1985-1986 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Transporation Subcommittee 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 11:7)
  - Working Committee: Initial Planning 1979-1980 (Box-folder 11:8)
  - Working Committee: Meeting September 19, 1979 (Box-folder 11:9)
  - Working Committee: Meeting October 17, 1979 (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Working Committee: Meeting October 31, 1979 (Box-folder 11:11)
  - Working Committee: Meeting November 14, 1979 (Box-folder 11:12)
  - Working Committee: Meeting November 28, 1979 (Box-folder 11:13)
  - Working Committee: Meeting December 12, 1979 (Box-folder 11:14)
  - Working Committee: Inaugural Conference 1980 (Box-folder 11:15)
  - Youth CommitteeWorking Committee: Initial Planning 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 11:16)
  - Youth Employment Advisory Committee 1983 (Box-folder 11:17)
- Series II Programs, Projects, and Reports 1979-1987
  - Atlanta Bus Trip 1981 (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Blacks and Jews in Search of Community Program 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Community Learning Week 1983-1984 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Community Learning Week 1984-1985 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - Community Learning Week 1985-1986 (Box-folder 12:5)
  - Community Projects 1982-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 12:6)
  - Community Solutions Congress 1984 (Box-folder 12:7)
  - Discussion Program at St. Matthias 1980 (Box-folder 12:8)
  - Economic Recovery Program 1981 (Box-folder 12:9)
  - Episcopal Urban Caucus 1979-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 12:10)
  - Federal Reserve Board/Housing Issue 1981-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 12:11)
  - Food and Nutrition Conference 1979 (Box-folder 13:1)
  - Food Stamp Program: Legal Proceedings 1979 (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Food Stamp Program: Interviews, Notes n.d. (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Food Stamp Program: Preliminary Guidelines 1979 (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Food Stamp Program: Public Meeting 1979 (Box-folder 13:5)
    Foundation Proposal Sampler: Examples from successful ... 1988
  - Grocery Shopping Study, Virginia Union University 1981 (Box-folder 13:6)
  - Hillside Court Food Co-op 1984 (Box-folder 13:7)
  - Historic Preservation Conference 1980 (Box-folder 13:8)
  - Junior League Bus Tour 1980 (Box-folder 13:9)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Dialogues 1982-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 13:10)
  - Methodist Consultation n.d. (Box-folder 13:11)
  - Metropolitan Ambulance Service 1981 (Box-folder 13:12)
  - New Federal Budget 1980-1981 (Box-folder 13:13)
  - New Federal Budget, Conference on 1980-1981 (Box-folder 13:14)
  - New Federal Budget, Conference on: Report 1982 (Box-folder 13:15)
  - Open High class: History and Culture of Africa 1982-1983 (Box-folder 14:1)
  - Propositions/Referendum 1980 (Box-folder 14:2)
    Public Education in Richmond Survey 1988
  - Racism Workshop 1984 (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Report: Richmond's Poor: Why are 77% Women and Childre? 1984 (Box-folder 14:4)
  - Richmond Area Manpower Planning System 1981 (Box-folder 14:5)
  - Rouse, James, developer 1981-1982 (Box-folder 14:6)
  - Save Our Shelter 1981 (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Summer Youth Emplooyment Program 1981-1985 (Box-folder 14:8)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program 1983-1985 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program: administrative 1983 (Box-folder 15:2)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program: Correspondence, memos 1982 (Box-folder 15:3)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program: Farmer Certificates of Award 1984 (Box-folder 15:4)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program: Music Extravaganza 1985 (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program: News articles, Rev. Jones'correspondence 1981-1983 (Box-folder 15:6)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program: other programs 1987 (Box-folder 15:7)
  - Summer Youth Employment Program: printed material 1982-1984 (Box-folder 15:8)
  - Tensions in the Richmond Community 1980-1981 (Box-folder 16:1)
  - Tensions Report notes 1981-1982. n.d. (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Urban Consultation 1980-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 16:3)
  - Walker, Maggie L. Celebration proposal 1982-1983 (Box-folder 16:4)
  - Wednesday's Child 1980-1981 (Box-folder 16:5)
  - Wednesday's Child 1982-1983 (Box-folder 16:6)
  - Wednesday's Child: Food Supplies 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 16:7)
  - Wednesday's Child: Jaycees 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 16:8)
  - Wednesday's Child: Originals 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 16:9)
  - Wednesday's Child: Transportation 1982, n.d. (Box-folder 16:10)
- Series III Proposals for Urban Projects 1978-1985
  - Carrington Street Connector Road 1978-1979 (Box-folder 17:1)
  - Freedom House 1982 (Box-folder 17:2)
  - Pre-Release Facility 1985 (Box-folder 17:3)
  - Proposed Downtown Richmond Plan 1984 (Box-folder 17:4)
  - Street Center Proposal (Box-folder 17:5)
- Series IV Housing 1979-1986
  - Apartments n.d. (Box-folder 17:6)
  - Census Data: VCU 1980 (Box-folder 17:7)
  - Census Tract Data 1980, 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 17:8)
  - Census Tracts 1978, n.d. (Box-folder 17:9)
  - Church Hill Area Revitalization Team (CHART) 1978-1980 (Box-folder 17:10)
  - CHART 1979-1980 (Box-folder 17:11)
  - CHART: By-laws and Articles of Incorporation 1979 (Box-folder 17:12)
  - CHART: Correspondence 1980-1982 (Box-folder 17:13)
  - CHART: Landmarks grant 1980 (Box-folder 17:14)
  - CHART: miscellaneous 1979-1980 (Box-folder 18:1)
  - CHART: notes, miscellaneous 1979-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 18:2)
  - CHART: notes, miscellaneous 191979-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 18:3)
  - CHART: Reports, meetings, notes 1980-1981 (Box-folder 18:4)
  - CHART: study areas n.d. (Box-folder 18:5)
  - Community Reinvestment 1983 (Box-folder 19:1)
  - Community Reinvestment Act 1985 (Box-folder 19:2)
  - Community Reinvestment Handbook 1979 (Box-folder 19:3)
  - Home Base 1984-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 19:4)
  - Home Mortgage Patterns in Richmond 1979 (Box-folder 19:5)
  - Housing: Assistance n.d. (Box-folder 19:6)
  - Housing: Guides n.d. (Box-folder 19:7)
  - Housing Investment Data 1979 (Box-folder 19:8)
  - Housing Investment Patterns in Richmond 1979 (Box-folder 19:9)
  - Housing: Miscellaneous 1975, 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 20:1)
  - Housing Opportunities Made Equal 1979-1980 (Box-folder 20:2)
  - Housing Rehabilitation Funding 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20:3)
  - Housing Rehabilitation Funding 1979-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 20:4)
  - Housing Rehabilitation Funding 1980-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 20:5)
  - Housing Rehabilitation Funding: newspaper articles 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20:6)
  - Landlord Tenant Commission 1983-1984 (Box-folder 21:1)
  - Mortgage Banking 1983 (Box-folder 21:2)
  - National Low-Income Housing 1984-1985 (Box-folder 21:3)
  - Neighborhood Assistance Act 1984-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 21:4)
  - Neighborhood Housing Service 1981-1982 (Box-folder 21:5)
  - Redlining 1983 n.d. (Box-folder 21:6)
  - Report: Comprehensive Neighborhood Improvement Project Work Program 1978 (Box-folder 21:7)
  - Report: Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation 1979 (Box-folder 21:8)
  - Richmond Redevelopment Housing Authority 1980 (Box-folder 21:9)
  - Richmond United Neighborhoods (RUN) 1982-1983 (Box-folder 21:10)
  - RUN Negotiations with F and M/VNB 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 21:11)
  - RUN Negotiations with RUI 1982-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 21:12)
  - RUN Proposed Bank Discussions 1978-1983 (Box-folder 21:13)
  - RUN Reinvestment in Housing 1982-1983 (Box-folder 21:14)
  - Virginia Housing Coalition 1983-1984 (Box-folder 21:15)
- Series V Women and the Family 1976-1986
  - Child Abuse 1983, n.d. (Box-folder 22:1)
  - Child Care 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 22:2)
  - Child Care and Employment 1988 (Box-folder 22:3)
  - Child Care Legislation 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 22:4)
  - Child Support 1981-1984, 1986 (Box-folder 22:5)
  - Family in Decline 1976-1977 (Box-folder 22:6)
  - Female-Headed Families in Virginia 1983 (Box-folder 22:7)
  - Feminization of Poverty: Drafts for Paper n.d. (Box-folder 22:8)
  - Feminization of Poverty: Statistics 1970/1980, 1981-1982, 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 22:9)
  - Feminization of Poverty: VCU Literature Search 1984 (Box-folder 22:10)
  - Infant Mortality 1982, 1984 (Box-folder 22:11)
  - Information and REferral Center (United Way) 1983-1984 (Box-folder 22:12)
  - Pay Equity 1980, 1984 n.d. (Box-folder 22:13)
  - Teenage Pregnancy 1984 (Box-folder 22:14)
  - Welfare Programs 1981, 1983-1984 n.d. (Box-folder 22:15)
  - Women: Career/Political Issues 1981-1984 (Box-folder 22:16)
  - Women: Jobs and Families 1981-1984 (Box-folder 22:17)
  - Women and Housing 1984 (Box-folder 22:18)
  - Women and Poverty: Articles, Notes 1983-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 23:1)
  - Women and Poverty Committee: Minutes 1984 (Box-folder 23:2)
  - Women and Poverty Conference 1985 (Box-folder 23:3)
  - Women and Poverty: news clippingsArticles, Notes 1984-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 23:4)
  - Women and Poverty Report 1984 (Box-folder 23:5)
  - Women and Poverty: Task Force 1984 (Box-folder 23:6)
  - Women, Children, and Welfare 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 23:7)
  - Women in the Face of Poverty 1982 (Box-folder 23:8)
  - Women's Issues 1984 (Box-folder 23:9)
- Series VI Other Urban Issues 1971-1985
  - Cross Buring 1983-1984 (Box-folder 24:1)
  - Homelessness 1984 (Box-folder 24:2)
  - Miscellaneous Articles 1980, 1984-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 24:3)
  - Nutrition Conference 1979 (Box-folder 24:4)
  - Police 1980 (Box-folder 24:5)
  - Printed material: annexation legislation 1979 (Box-folder 24:6)
  - Printed material: nutrition 1979 (Box-folder 24:7)
  - Printed material: Offender Aid and Restoration 1979 (Box-folder 24:8)
  - Racism in America 1971-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 25:1)
  - Research Clippings: adult/nursing homes (Box-folder 25:2)
  - Research Clippings: annexation legislation (Box-folder 25:3)
  - Research Clippings: banking (Box-folder 25:4)
  - Research Clippings: Black activities (Box-folder 25:5)
  - Research Clippings: census redistricting (Box-folder 25:6)
  - Research Clippings: child abuse (Box-folder 25:7)
  - Research Clippings: The Church (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Research Clippings: City Council (Box-folder 25:9)
  - Research Clippings: City government, U.S. (Box-folder 25:10)
  - Research Clippings: crime (Box-folder 25:11)
  - Research Clippings: employees, public (Box-folder 25:12)
  - Research Clippings: energy/VEPCO (Box-folder 25:13)
  - Research Clippings: environment (Box-folder 25:14)
  - Research Clippings: The Family (Box-folder 25:15)
  - Research Clippings: food stamps (Box-folder 25:16)
  - Research Clippings: fuel (Box-folder 25:17)
  - Research Clippings: fuel funds (Box-folder 25:18)
  - Research Clippings: government (Box-folder 26:1)
  - Research Clippings: Henrico/Chesterfield counties (Box-folder 26:2)
  - Research Clippings: highways/roads (Box-folder 26:3)
  - Research Clippings: housing (Box-folder 26:4)
  - Research Clippings: lobbyists (Box-folder 26:5)
  - Research Clippings: Lutheran Resources Commission News Brief 1980 (Box-folder 26:6)
  - Research Clippings: mentally ill (Box-folder 26:7)
  - Research Clippings: miscellaneous (Box-folder 26:8)
  - Research Clippings: Neighborhood Assistance Act (Box-folder 26:9)
  - Research Clippings: Oregon Hill (Box-folder 26:10)
  - Research Clippings: people (Box-folder 26:11)
  - Research Clippings: politics, Virginia (Box-folder 26:12)
  - Research Clippings: prisons (Box-folder 26:13)
  - Research Clippings: programs, community (Box-folder 26:14)
  - Research Clippings: reprints (Box-folder 26:15)
  - Research Clippings: Richmond city government (Box-folder 26:16)
  - Research Clippings: social issues (Box-folder 26:17)
  - Research Clippings: tax cut referendum (Box-folder 26:18)
  - Research Clippings: taxes/spending (Box-folder 26:19)
  - Research Clippings: urban renewal (Box-folder 26:20)
  - Research Clippings: Virginia Municipal League policy statement 1980 (Box-folder 26:21)
  - Research Clippings: Virginia Municipal League Tax Task Force Report (Box-folder 26:22)
  - Research Clippings: welfare (Box-folder 26:23)
  - Research Clippings: zoning (Box-folder 26:24)
  - Richmond Neighborhood: Journal Article 1983 (Box-folder 27:1)
  - Richmond Theatres 1981 (Box-folder 27:2)
- Series VII Public Relations 1979-1985
  - News Articles concerning RUI 1980-1985 (Box-folder 27:3)
  - News Leader editorials 1979-1980 (Box-folder 27:4)
  - Newsletter 1980-1981, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 27:5)
  - Newsletter: Material 1980-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 27:6)
  - Newsletter: Reference, Rough Drafts n.d. (Box-folder 27:7)
  - Press Releases 1979-1983 (Box-folder 27:8)
  - Public Relations 1981-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 27:9)
  - Public Relations: Area Media Report 1980-1985 (Box-folder 27:10)
  - Public Relations: Reference Lists n.d. (Box-folder 27:11)
  - Revitalization News 1983-1984 (Box-folder 27:12)
- Series VIII Other Organizations 1979-1988
  - African Arts and Culture Collective 1981-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 28:1)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai Brith 1983-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 28:2)
  - Church Hill Reunion Committee 1985 (Box-folder 28:3)
  - City Venture Corporation 1981-1982 (Box-folder 28:4)
  - Commission on Human Relations 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 28:5)
  - Common Cause 1984-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 28:6)
  - Council of Organizations 1984-1985 (Box-folder 28:7)
  - Downtown Cooperative Ministry 1979 (Box-folder 28:8)
  - East End Planning Committee 1984-1985 (Box-folder 28:9)
  - Episcopal Urban Caucus 1979 (Box-folder 28:10)
  - Federated Arts 1980 (Box-folder 28:11)
  - Historic Preservation and the Minority Community 1983-1985 (Box-folder 28:12)
  - Human Rights Coalition 1984 (Box-folder 29:1)